Welcome to this free online class on
machine learning. Machine learning is one
欢迎来到机器学习免费在线课程。机器学习是
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
of the most exciting recent technologies.
And in this class, you learn about the
目前最激动人心的技术之一。本课程中，你将学习
state of the art and also gain practice
implementing and deploying these algorithms
机器学习的发展，并且实现这些算法。
yourself. You've probably use a learning
algorithm dozens of times a day without
你每天都要多次使用学习，但并没有意识到。
knowing it. Every time you use a web
search engine like Google or Bing to
每次当你使用Google或Bing等搜索引擎时，
search the internet, one of the reasons
that works so well is because a learning
它能给出如此满意的结果，原因之一就是使用了学习算法。
algorithm, one implemented by Google or
Microsoft, has learned how to rank web
由Google或微软实现的算法学会如何给网页排序。
pages. Every time you use Facebook or
Apple's photo typing application and it
每次你使用Facebook或苹果的相片分类功能，
recognizes your friends' photos, that's
also machine learning. Every time you read
它能识别出你朋友的相片，这也是机器学习。每次当你阅读邮件时，
your email and your spam filter saves you
from having to wade through tons of spam
你的垃圾邮件过滤器帮助你过滤大量的垃圾邮件，
email, that's also a learning algorithm.
For me one of the reasons I'm excited is
这也是学习算法。对我而言，我兴奋的原因之一是
the AI dream of someday building machines
as intelligent as you or me. We're a long
AI的梦想就是有一天能建造像你我一样智能的机器。
way away from that goal, but many AI
researchers believe that the best way to
我们离这个目标还很远，但是许多AI研究者相信实现这个目标的最好方法
towards that goal is through learning
algorithms that try to mimic how the human
就是采用学习算法试图模拟人类大脑是如何学习的。
brain learns. I'll tell you a little bit
about that too in this class. In this
在本课程中，我将会向你们介绍部分这方面的内容。
class you learn about state-of-the-art
machine learning algorithms. But it turns
本课程中，你将学习机器学习算法的发展。
out just knowing the algorithms and
knowing the math isn't that much good if
但是，仅知道算法以及算法的数学含义，
you don't also know how to actually get
this stuff to work on problems that you
却不知道如何在你关心的问题上运用，是远远不够的。
care about. So, we've also spent a lot
of time developing exercises for you to
因此，我们也会花很多时间让你练习如何
implement each of these algorithms and
see how they work for yourself. So why is
实现每一个算法，如何被你所用。
machine learning so prevalent today?
It turns out that machine learning is a
这就是为什么机器学习如此流行。机器学习
field that had grown out of the field of
AI, or artificial intelligence. We wanted
是从AI发展出来的一个领域。我们想
to build intelligent machines and it turns
out that there are a few basic things that
建造智能机器，那就是说我们要编程使机器能做很多基本的事情，
we could program a machine to do such as
how to find the shortest path from A to B.
比如找到从A到B的最短路径。
But for the most part we just did not know
how to write AI programs to do the more
但大多数情况下，我们不知道如何编写AI程序使机器做更多
interesting things such as web search or
photo tagging or email anti-spam. There
有趣的事情，如网页搜索、相片标记、反垃圾邮件。
was a realization that the only way to do
these things was to have a machine learn
人们认识到做到这些事情，唯一的方法就是使机器本事学习如何去做。
to do it by itself. So, machine learning
was developed as a new capability for
因此，机器学习是计算机需要开发的一项新能力，
computers and today it touches many
segments of industry and basic science.
并且它设计工业和基础科学中的许多内容。
For me, I work on machine learning and
in a typical week I might end up talking to
对我而言，我研究机器学习，并且在有代表性的一周中，我可能会与
helicopter pilots, biologists, a bunch
of computer systems people (so my
直升飞机飞行员，生物学家，很多计算机系统的人员交流
colleagues here at Stanford) and averaging
two or three times a week I get email from
并且每周2~3次与
people in industry from Silicon Valley
contacting me who have an interest in
硅谷工业界的人员互通email，他们对在他们的问题上
applying learning algorithms to their own
problems. This is a sign of the range of
应用学习算法感兴趣。以下是一些
problems that machine learning touches.
There is autonomous robotics, computational
机器学习涉及的领域，自主机器人，计算生物学，
biology, tons of things in Silicon Valley
that machine learning is having an impact
以及其它一些被机器学习影响的领域。
on. Here are some other examples of
machine learning. There's database mining.
还有一些其它的例子，如数据挖掘。
One of the reasons machine learning has so
pervaded is the growth of the web and the
机器学习如此普遍的原因之一就是网络的快速发展和
growth of automation. All this means that
we have much larger data sets than ever
自动化技术的快速发展。这意味着我们拥有了前所未有的大量的数据集。
before. So, for example tons of Silicon
Valley companies are today collecting web
因此，现在大量硅谷公司收集网络点击数据，
click data, also called clickstream data,
and are trying to use machine learning
被称为点击流数据，并试图采用机器学习算法
algorithms to mine this data to understand
the users better and to serve the users
来挖掘数据，更好地理解用户，并更好地为用户服务。
better, that's a huge segment of
Silicon Valley right now. Medical
这占目前硅谷工作的很大部分。
records. With the advent of automation, we
now have electronic medical records, so if
医疗记录。随着自动化的出现，现在我们使用电子医疗记录，
we can turn medical records into medical
knowledge, then we can start to understand
因此，假如我们能将医疗记录转化为医疗知识，那我们就能更好地理解疾病。
disease better. Computational biology.
With automation again, biologists are
计算生物学。还是因为自动化，生物学家
collecting lots of data about gene
sequences, DNA sequences, and so on, and
收集了大量的数据，关于基因序列，DNA序列等。
machines learning algorithms are giving us
a much better understanding of the human
机器学习算法让我们更好地理解基因组，
genome, and what it means to be human.
And in engineering as well, in all fields of
以及它对人类的意义。在工程学中，在工程学所有的领域，
engineering, we have larger and larger,
and larger and larger data sets, that
我们有越来越大，越来越大的数据集，
we're trying to understand using learning
algorithms. A second range of machinery
我们正设法采用学习算法来理解。
applications is ones that we cannot
program by hand. So for example, I've
机器应用的第二个领域是我们无法手动编写程序。例如，
worked on autonomous helicopters for many
years. We just did not know how to write a
我们已经在自动直升飞机领域研究了很多年，仍不知道如何编写
computer program to make this helicopter
fly by itself. The only thing that worked
计算机程序使得直升飞机自己飞行。唯一有用的
was having a computer learn by itself how
to fly this helicopter. [Helicopter whirling]
就是使计算机自己学习如何使直升飞机飞行。
Handwriting recognition. It turns out one
of the reasons it's so inexpensive today to
手写体识别。今天，邮寄不再昂贵的原因之一，
route a piece of mail across the
countries, in the US and internationally,
无论在美国或国际上，
is that when you write an envelope like
this, it turns out there's a learning
就是当你写好信封后，有学习算法
algorithm that has learned how to read your
handwriting so that it can automatically
来学习如何读取你的手写体，使得它能自动地
route this envelope on its way, and so it
costs us a few cents to send this thing
给你的信规划路线。因此，邮寄几千公里之外的信也只需要花费几分钱。
thousands of miles. And in fact if you've
seen the fields of natural language
事实上，假如你知道自然语言处理
processing or computer vision,
these are the fields of AI pertaining to
或计算机视觉，这些都是AI中有关
understanding language or understanding
images. Most of natural language processing
理解语言或理解图像的领域。今天，大部分的自然语言处理和
and most of computer vision today is
applied machine learning. Learning
大部分的计算机视觉采用机器学习。
algorithms are also widely used for self-
customizing programs. Every time you go to
学习算法还应用在自我定制程序中。每次当你使用
Amazon or Netflix or iTunes Genius, and it
recommends the movies or products and
亚马逊或Netflix或iTunes天才，它就会推荐电影或产品或音乐给你，
music to you, that's a learning algorithm.
If you think about it they have million
这就是学习算法。假如你想象一下，他们有百万用户，
users; there is no way to write a million
different programs for your million users.
不可能为百万用户编写百万个不同的程序。
The only way to have software give these
customized recommendations is to become
用软件给出这些客户推荐的唯一方法就是
learn by itself to customize itself to
your preferences. Finally learning
自我学习并为你定制你偏爱的东西。
algorithms are being used today to
understand human learning and to
另外，今天学习算法还被使用来理解人类的学习
understand the brain. We'll talk about
how researches are using this to make
和大脑。我们将会讨论研究者是如何使用这些来
progress towards the big AI dream. A few
months ago, a student showed me an article
朝着AI梦前进的。几个月前，一个学生给我看了篇文章，
on the top twelve IT skills. The skills
that information technology hiring
列出了12个IT技术。这些技术是信息科技雇主
managers cannot say no to. It was a
slightly older article, but at the top of
最喜爱的。这篇文章有点旧了，但是在这张表中，
this list of the twelve most desirable IT
skills was machine learning. Here at
机器学习位列第一。
Stanford, the number of recruiters
that contact me asking if I know any
在斯坦福，联系我的招聘人员，需要的机器学习毕业的学生
graduating machine learning students
is far larger than the machine learning
的数量远大于每年毕业的机器学习的学生。
students we graduate each year. So I
think there is a vast, unfulfilled demand
因此，我认为这项技术有大量的未完成的需求。
for this skill set, and this is a great time to
be learning about machine learning, and I
这也是一个学习机器学习的好时机。
hope to teach you a lot about machine
learning in this class. In the next video,
我希望能在这门课中教给你机器学习的知识。在下一个视频中，
we'll start to give a more formal
definition of what is machine learning.
我们将开始给出机器学习的更正式的定义。
And we'll begin to talk about the main
types of machine learning problems and
我们将开始谈到机器学习问题的主要类型，及算法。
algorithms. You'll pick up some of the
main machine learning terminology, and
你们将会学到一些主要的机器学习术语，
start to get a sense of what are the
different algorithms, and when each one
及开始理解不同的机器学习算法，及每个算法在什么时候是合适的。
might be appropriate.
也许管用。